UTHMAN MUTIULLAHI

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Uthmanbusayomi@gmail.com | +2348136055016 | Oyo, Nigeria



CERTIFICATION

- GRAPHICS AND VISUAL **DESIGN** Ascent 8760Multimedia August-October 2023
- PRODUCT DESIGN **Perxels** February- August 2023
- WEBSITE **DEVELOPMENT** Course Kevin Powell's YouTube Tutorial September 2021(Completed)
- WEB DEVELOPMENT Angela Yu's Udemy Web **Development Bootcamp** August 2021(Completed)
- ADVANCE WEB **DEVELOPMENT GbTech Computer Education** March 2021(Completed)
- HUMAN RELATIONSHIP **MANAGEMENT New Horizons** 2018-2019

SKILLS

HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, React, AngularJS and Vue.js, CSS preprocessor such as SASS and LESS.UI/UX, Adobe Photoshop and Adobe illustrator

EDUCATION

BTech.Agricultural Economics and Extension Ladoke Akintola University of Technology Ogbomoso, Oyo state. (2011-2016)

SUMMARY

A result-oriented and quality-focused professional with versed knowledge of angular JS, React, Typescript, JavaScript HTML5, CSS, Adobe illustrator and Adobe Photoshop to develop an aesthetic and user-friendly software. Over the years, I have demonstrated problem solving and analytical skills to resolve identified complex issues and provided the best user experience systems. As a passionate web developer. I am committed to fast learning, deliver quality and continued professional development.

EXPERIENCE

FRONTEND ENGINEER

2023-PRESENT

Upwork

- Solving high frontend problems of many reputable organizations and individuals as a freelancer.
- Managing progress and tasks asynchronously with tools such as documents, GitHub and ticket system.
- Developed multiple landing page for small businesses and top companies.

FRONTEND ENGINEER

2022-2023

New Horizons

- Leading the program for teaching interns how to write accessible, wellstructured, and semantic HTML.
- Orientate interns on high efficiency skills in writing modern CSS for responsive UIs.
- Collaborate with other designers and developers to solve problems

FRONTEND DEVELOPER (INTERN)

2021-2022

GB Tech

- Collaborate with designers to deliver responsive, tasteful and friendly UIs.
- Collaborate with developers to ingrate RESTful or GRPC APIs to front-end applications.
- Decided the suitable designs for user's interface.
- Lead initiatives to make impactful UI/UX

PROJECTS

CODEWITHME

• CodeWithMe is a launch pad website for software engineering training. It was developed using [HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, and JavaScript]

GRAPHERTUSH

A photography company website. https://graphertush.netlify.app/index.html

DAKULTECH WEBSITE

• A responsive landing page built from scratch using HTML, CSS, Bootstraps and JavaScript with feature including About Us and Contact to enable user have more information about the page.

https://code-with-me-nine.vercel.app/index.html

TEEHUB

• A gadget store page built to enable B2C interaction. The website display gadgets and specifications to enable orders and sales of product by potential buyers.

https://dakultech.github.io/TeeHubHome/

DEE EMBEEZ

• E commerce website.

https://de-embeez.netlify.app/

TAICOIN CEX

 A crypto exchange website built with HTML, JavaScript, NuxtJS and PHP to promote conversion of crypto coin to valuable currency. https://tacoin.com.ng/index.php

BOARD AND BRICKS

 A modern website with aesthetic design and highly responsive built with HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Angular. https://boardsandbricks.com.ng/

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

https://github.com/DakulTech

REFEREES

Available on request